

BY ALEXANDER CHESSER



Thanks for taking the time to read my resume – the proper content is down below but I wanted to draw your attention to the following points specifically:

Have a very strong background in building distributed systems using Java or other object-oriented languages such as C#, C++, Python, or Golang

- 10 years in C# building cloud and distributed systems. I'm reasonably comfortable in Java as it is syntactically often a copy and paste of C# (with some subtleties)
- Current reading "Designing Data-Intensive Applications" and "Designing Distributed Systems"

Have a deep understanding of good software design patterns, mixed with a healthy passion for refactoring and keeping things simple

 Passionate? Does hosting around 15 hours of youtube shows specifically about software architecture count as passionate? But wait <a href="there's more">there's more</a>! Seriously, I'm super into this stuff.

Have a keen commitment to test-driven development

I love automated testing – I am experienced in writing testing in my personal work. However my
previous employer expressly forbade unit tests. I'm happy to be somewhere now that DOES
support testing.

Experienced building and leveraging mid-tier services

I have both written and leveraged systems that sit between other systems

Are clear, concise, and effective in both written and verbal communications

Write clean reusable interfaces that maximize functionality while minimizing maintenance

Are responsible, take accountability, and work well in, and across, teams

Enjoy working in an environment with lots of context and minimal guidance Are ruthlessly pragmatic and know how to ship high-value features quickly

You have strong convictions and are open to being convinced otherwise

Resonate with our unique culture

Evaluate multiple opportunities for time and effort to identify and invest in those with the greatest opportunity for impact on the organization

Improve the team and organization you're part of, rather than accepting the status quo

Automate yourself out of critical support or mundane tasks to enable our team to scale

Learn and grow from working with stunning colleagues while helping them grow from your experiences and perspectives.

 In an effort to be clear, concise (and ruthlessly pragmatic) I'm just gonna say "yup" to all of these ones

Completely own the design, implementation, and dev/ops for your deliverables

 With 20 years in technology and over 10 as a technical architect I am very comfortable owning a solution from green field to maintenance.

Learn the ins-and-outs of our business and how Netflix manages money

- No word of a lie, I'm super interested in and excited by finance in general and film finance specifically. I've literally got a copy of Film Production Management 101 (by Deborah Patz) sitting on my bookshelf that I picked up ~15 years ago.
- As I mentioned in a twitter DM I sent you, one of my parents is an accountant and I grew up around all these sorts of finance terms. I really do enjoy *genuinely* the space.

Working knowledge of deploying cloud based applications

• While at Klick I owned the complete transformation of one client's transition from manual deployments to an Azure based CI/CD system.

An understanding of concepts like concurrency and reactive programming

I haven't quite "signed the manifesto" or anything but I think it is super cool. I'm playing around
with Kafka quite a bit nowadays and it is really exciting. Maybe I'll sign when I'm a bit more
confident and comfortable with it all. I get it though. It makes sense.

# ALEXANDER CHESSER

Senior Staff Developer & Technical Architect

#### CONTACT



647-863-4164



alex.chesser@gmail.com



github.com/alexchesser



stackoverflow.com/users/398055



linkedin.com/in/alex-chesser

#### **SKILLS**

- C#, JAVASCRIPT, PHP, **PYTHON**
- SQLSERVER, POSTGRES
- AZURE. AWS
- GIT, SVN
- MVC, UNITY 3D, CORDOVA
- WCF, REST, SOAP
- ANGULAR, JQUERY, NODEJS
- WORDPRESS, UMBRACO, DRUPAL

#### **PROFILE**

As a highly engaged all-rounder I'd expect to show a strong performance in providing solutions in any tech position while mentoring and growing the team around me.

While on a short (five year) mid-career stint as a high school teacher, I learned two critical life lessons that stay with me to this day.

The first is that how you accomplish something is often more important than what you accomplish. To that end, I make every effort to be honest, respectful and, friendly with my colleagues.

The second is that the hardest working kid in the room will beat out the smartest every single time.

Nothing beats a hard-working smart kid who is nice to the people around them.

#### CLIENTS



























#### **EDUCATION**

#### Bachelor of Education

2003 - 2004

University of Western Ontario

### Bachelor of Arts - Psychology

1995 - 2000

Carlton University

### **PROFESSIONAL** DEVELOPMENT

## Unity Mastery + VR Wizard

2019

Unity3d.college

### Health Information Management 2016

Ryerson University

#### **EXPERIENCE**



## Senior Staff Developer – Zensurance

2021 - Present

As staff engineer my focus is on working across functional areas to improve and level up the overall engineering practice of the organization. To coach, mentor and, advocate for the team as a whole. To spread best practices, assisting with improving overall technical quality.



#### **kli** Technical Architect – Klick Health

**Sk** 2016 - 2021

Technical Lead on multiple projects in the digital marketing space. Managed the work of a team of developers to ensure successful on-time delivery of projects.



### Full Stack Developer – Klick Health

2015 - 2016

Technical Lead on multiple projects in the digital marketing space. Managed the work of a team of developers to ensure successful on-time delivery of projects.



## Genome Developer – Klick Health

2014 - 2015

Working on Klick's core systems while safely replacing legacy systems.



## Application Developer – Klick Health

2011 - 2014

- Object Oriented Web apps C# / .NET
- Wordpress, Drupal, Silverpop and Facebook API
- Native iOS application development.



## Web Developer - PPX.com

2009 - 2011

Working in the affiliate marketing space to drive and A/B test high volume traffic into a various affiliate offers. Platform was a LAMP stack including Ajax, jQuery, PHPUnit, MVC Frameworks and SVN.

#### Teacher – The Eastwood School

2006 - 2009

Teaching students aged 11 to 16 Computer Skills

Teacher – St Thomas More School for Boys

Teaching Computer Skills to students aged 11 to 19

N(2RTEL

## Programmer Analyst – Nortel Networks

1999 - 2001

Database design and administration, MS SQL Server, ASP programming, Visual Basic for Applications, Automation of report generation in Excel. PERL / CGI scripting in a UNIX environment.

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS & OPEN SOURCE

Ongoing technological experimentation and projects is a core pillar in my personal strategy to keep my skills fresh, current and to keep pushing me to be at the top of my game.

- In the past I've built weekend-websites that used nodejs + mongodb to pull tens of thousands of hits a day on an aws nano sized server.
- Fixed new-user documentation in Kubernetes around a missing step saving future developers hours of googling. https://github.com/kubernetes/kubernetes/pull/17552
- Fixed the Microsoft aspnet dockerfile to speed the container's redeploy from minutes to seconds ... like containers are supposed to behave <a href="https://github.com/OmniSharp/generator-aspnet/pull/530">https://github.com/OmniSharp/generator-aspnet/pull/530</a>
- Solved an issue in the android side of a mobile crossplatform cordova pdf generator plugin. <a href="https://github.com/cesarvr/pdf-generator/pull/31">https://github.com/cesarvr/pdf-generator/pull/31</a>
- Wrote an Oculus Quest finger-tracking module proof of concept which has pseudo full-body VR tracking with a custom avatar, as well as actual individual finger-level tracking
  - https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=50-\_6e5QZ1s
- I have been working on some automated systems for improving page-load speeds by trimming vendor CSS and JS file. When asked, the creator of google's lighthouse performance tool called it "interesting" https://github.com/vendor-coverage-workflow
- I'm currently in the process of starting a podcast of interviews of professional developers with an eye to covering topics about the business and craft of software development. You can get a sense of who I am before wasting your time on an interview! (Please Subscribe) https://www.youtube.com/c/lgtmshipit
- In preparation for the pending tsunami of code interviews that I haven't written in about 10 years, I started a repo of code interview prep. You can examine my interview questions before even speaking to me! https://github.com/AlexChesser/coding-interview-practice